Raleigh, NC 27610 | Phone: 252-206-6023 | Email: impulseimg@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/m-neal | github.com/Matthew-Neal | matthew-neal.github.io/Portfolio/

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- ✓ Fully integrated inventory to Cloud based and synced to Shopify site and pushing to Amazon, Ebay, and Google
- ✓ Slashed product/supply costs for World of R/C; created and increased margins on branded products from 25% to 85%
- ✓ Managed and built the team to grow overall sales for World of R/C 20x to \$2.25M annually
- ✓ Completed an inventory record transfer of 18K+ items into QuickBooks Pro and QuickBooks POS
- ✓ Planned/executed yield research/profit projection improvement projects that generated up to \$5M in additional revenue for Mountaire Farms

QUALIFICATIONS & SKILLS

HTML, Node, CSS

JavaScript, ES5, ES6, jQuery

VS Studio

Online Order Management & Fulfillment

Purchasing/Procurement

High-Volume Inventory Management

Distributor & Vendor Communications

Workflow Scheduling

Customer Service

Driving Business Expansion & Sales Growth

Strategic Planning

Intuit QuickBooks & POS

Adobe Photography Suite

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Detail-oriented purchasing and inventory management specialist with ten years of experience in operations and financial management. Excels in planning and executing programs and projects that optimize inventory management, slash operating costs, and maximize profits. Provides excellent customer service and drives efficient project completion to exceed production goals. Recently certified in full Stack Web Development and experience with Shopify platform.

WORK EXPERIENCE

World of R/C Parts & Supplies, Wilson, NC

General Manager, **Integration and inventory Specialist** 05/2012 to Present – Ensure operational efficiency by managing inventory, forecasting for optimal cash flow, and providing project management leadership. Recent focus is working on and leading the team for online presence. Utilizing applications and API's to integrate inventory to Shopify website and other online platforms.

- Expanded company reach via website, eBay, Amazon.com, and management of contracts with various manufacturers
- Completed inventory transfer to cloud to sync with a new Shopify website deployment along with pushing to eBay, Amazon, and Google
- Project manager including overseeing a team to complete website deployment and goals of entering other markets such as Amazon
- Troubleshoot, document, and test technical product issues for customers; provide technical product training for employees and customers

Impulse Imaging, Raleigh, NC

Owner, 11/2011 to Present – Manage a high-quality photography printing business serving over 100 customers nationwide. Manage in-house inventory and product production, as well as tax and P&L records. Create custom wood frames for clients.

4Fifty8 Acquisitions, Raleigh, NC

Account Manager, 08/2011 to 04/2012 — Applied excellent follow-up and marketing techniques to promote fortune 500 clients, manage B2B sales, secure new business accounts, and ensure client retention. Built high-performing marketing and sales teams by interviewing and training new candidates.

Mountaire Farms of North Carolina, Lumber Bridge, NC

Area Supervisor, 04/2010 to 08/2011 — Oversaw quality production, including management of 50 employees, to produce product for major customers, including Kraft, Sarah Lee, and Boar's Head. Ensured compliance with FDA standards in the highest-demand department.

- Led meetings and conducted training to ensure adherence to safety protocols and quality-control standards; managed HACCP, SSOP, and CAPA documentation
- Managed production equipment for grading, sorting, and density scanning

EDUCATION

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp Certificate: University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 2020

BS in Agricultural Business Management, Minor in Economics: North Carolina State University, 2009